Guide to the Alexander Cuningham Papers, 1740-1918
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Alexander Cuningham papers 1740-1918
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Cuningham, Alexander, d. ca. 1850.
6,371 Items
Merchant, from Petersburg, Va.
Business records and some personal correspondence of four generations of the Cuningham family, including Robert Cuningham; Alexander Cuningham, and his brother, Richard M. Cuningham; the latter's son, John Wilson Cuningham; and grandson, John Somerville Cuningham, all merchants and planters. The early papers center around Alexander and Richard's success as commission merchants for cotton and tobacco in Petersburg, Va., and the firm's planting interests in Person County, N.C. The collection also contains a few family letters, including some from Alexander Jr. while a student at the University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, and from another son at Leasburg Academy, Caswell County, N.C. The papers of John Somerville Cuningham concern his work as a field agent for the Bureau of Crop Estimates, U.S. Dept. of Agriculture, local politics, and family matters.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Alexander Cuningham Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift.
Biographical Note
Merchant, from Petersburg, Va.
Collection Overview
Business records and some personal correspondence of four generations of the Cuningham family, including Robert Cuningham; Alexander Cuningham, and his brother, Richard M. Cuningham; the latter's son, John Wilson Cuningham; and grandson, John Somerville Cuningham, all merchants and planters. The early papers center around Alexander and Richard's success as commission merchants for cotton and tobacco in Petersburg, Va., and the firm's planting interests in Person County, N.C. The collection also contains a few family letters, including some from Alexander Jr. while a student at the University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, and from another son at Leasburg Academy, Caswell County, N.C. The papers of John Somerville Cuningham concern his work as a field agent for the Bureau of Crop Estimates, U.S. Dept. of Agriculture, local politics, and family matters.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Cuningham, John Somerville, 1861-1922
Cunningham, John Wilson, 1820-1887
Cuningham, Richard M.
Cuningham, Robert, d. ca. 1788
Cunningham family
Leasburg Academy (Caswell County, N.C.)
United States -- Dept. of Agriculture -- Officials and employees
University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill -- Students
Agriculture -- North Carolina -- Person County
Agriculture -- Virginia
Cotton -- Marketing
Merchants -- Virginia -- Petersburg
Merchants -- North Carolina -- Person County
Tobacco -- Marketing
Universities and colleges -- North Carolina
Commission merchants -- Virginia
Person County (N.C.) -- History
Petersburg (Va.) -- History
Virginia -- Economic conditions
Contents of Collection
- Alexander Cuningham Papers, 1740-1918, (14 boxes, 23 volumes)
  - Papers, 1740-1818 April (Box 1)
  - Papers, 1818 May-1820 (Box 2)
  - Papers, 1821-1823 (Box 3)
  - Papers, 1824-1825 Feb. (Box 4)
  - Papers, 1825 March-June (Box 5)
  - Papers, 1825 July-Dec. (Box 6)
  - Papers, 1826 (Box 7)
  - Papers, 1827-1829 (Box 8)
  - Papers, 1830-1840 (Box 9)
  - Papers, 1841-1850 (Box 10)
  - Papers, 1851-1857 (Box 11)
  - Papers, 1858-1915 (Box 12)
  - Papers, 1916-1918 and undated (Box 13)
  - Papers, undated (Box 14)
  - Clippings
  - Volumes
  - Volume (Volume F:833)
  - Volume (Volume F:838)
  - Volume (Volume F:841)
  - Volume (Volume F:842)
  - Volume (Volume F:843)
  - Volume (Volume F:845)
  - Volume (Volume F:846)
  - Volume (Volume F:848)
  - Volume (Volume F:850)
  - Volume (Volume F:852)
  - Volume (Volume F:856)
  - Volume (Volume F:864)
  - Volume (Volume F:869)
  - Volume (Volume L:840)
  - Volume (Volume L:844)
  - Volume (Volume L:847)
  - Volume (Volume L:849)
  - Volume (Volume L:851)
  - Volume (Volume L:854)
  - Volume (Volume L:859)
  - Volume (Volume L:860)
  - Volume (Volume L:861)
  - Volume (Volume M:837)